Hey everybody. Welcome to this A2
English listening practice video. You
can use this video to practice your
listening and comprehension as I speak.
Before we start, remember to subscribe
to the channel, click on the bell, and
follow us on Instagram. You ready? So,
today I'm going to talk about weddings.
I think that this is a fun topic because
there are so many customs and traditions
when it comes to weddings. And it's also
interesting because different countries'
weddings could be considered a
reflection of those countries. So, let's
talk about some of the most important
traditions involved in American
weddings. First, you have to understand
that traditionally, weddings are a big
deal in the US. Little girls often dream
about their future wedding day and about
wearing their beautiful wedding dress.
The wedding dress is one of the most
important parts of the American wedding,
so women spend a lot of time trying to
find the perfect gown. The bride
attracts most of the attention at
weddings, so of course, she wants to
look as stunning as possible. The groom
doesn't get quite as much attention as
the bride, and so the groom's suit isn't
quite as important as the bride's dress.
If you've watched American movies that
include wedding scenes, you've probably
noticed that both the bride and the
groom have people standing next to them
at the ceremony. These people are called
the bridesmaids and the groomsmen. The
most important bridesmaid is called the
maid of honor, and the most important
groomsman is called the best man. In the
US, it's a big honor to be asked to be
the best man or the maid of honor at a
wedding. Usually, both of these people
give a speech during the reception. The
reception is the word we use for the
party that comes after the ceremony. In
the US, both the ceremony and the
reception are important, but the
ceremony is especially important. In
other countries like Mexico, the
ceremony is not important. Many people
skip the ceremony and just show up for
the reception. In the US, nobody would
do that. Everyone wants to see the
ceremony. There are several important
elements to the ceremony in American
weddings. For example, there's usually a
flower girl or a ring bearer. A flower
girl is a young girl that walks down the
aisle tossing flowers on the ground. And
a ring bearer is a young boy that
carries the rings down the aisle. Then
there's the minister who officiates the
wedding and does most of the talking.
And one other important element is the
wedding vows. The vows are the promises
that the bride and groom make to each
other in front of everyone. It's often
an emotional experience when the bride
and groom read their vows. And then
after the ceremony, everyone goes to the
reception hall for the party. Sometimes,
the reception hall is at the same
location as the ceremony, but other
times it's not. And so people have to
drive there after the ceremony. During
the reception, there's a big catered
meal. When I say that the meal is
catered, this means that it's provided
by some outside company. Then after the
meal, there are some speeches and of
course dancing. Later on at some point,
everyone stops to eat some wedding cake
and to watch the bouquet toss. The
bouquet toss is the custom where the
bride throws her bouquet of flowers over
her head and then all of the single
girls who are at the wedding try to
catch the bouquet. It's thought that the
girl who catches the bouquet will be the
next person to get married. It's a fun
tradition. Lastly, let me just mention
the gifts. In many American weddings,
the bride and groom register their
wedding at a store like Walmart, Target,
or even Amazon. Then the guests can
choose a present from that store's items
that the bride and groom put on their
wish list. This way, the couple knows
that they'll get the presents that they
really want. All right, that's all for
today. Leave a comment and tell me
something interesting about weddings in
your country. And remember to subscribe
to the channel, click on the bell, and
follow us on Instagram for more English
tips and lessons. I'll see you next
time.